MELHEM EL DIRANI

Front-end developer

SUMMARY

Melhem is a self-taught front-end web developer. He has extensive knowledge of JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Node.js as well as significant experience with popular libraries and frameworks such as React.



Maximos s

Maximos st. Saida, Lebanon



melhemdirani@hotmail.com



https://melhemdirani.github.io/Melhem/



+961 71 523 153



https://www.linkedin.com/in/melhem-el-dirani-8A657BA5/?_l=en_US

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS

TOOLS

- GitHub
- WordPress
- Visual Studio Code

LIBRARIES/ API

- React
- Node.js
- Material-UI
- SASS

STORAGE

Firebase

FRAMEWORK

- Redux
- GraphQL
- Apollo
- Express

METHODOLOGIES

- Agile Development
- REST API
- Unit Testing

EXPERIENCE

Intern Frontend Web Developer, Sicilia Mia, 2021 to Present

- · Reviewing application requirements and interface designs.
- Developing and implementing highly-responsive user interface components using React concepts.
- Writing application interface codes using JavaScript following React.js workflows.
- Troubleshooting interface software and debugging application codes.
- Developing and implementing front-end architecture to support user interface concepts.
- Monitoring and improving front-end performance.

Web development Teacher, Remote, 2021 to present

- Guide and assist fresh students in their study plan.
- Teach new concepts, languages and frameworks.
- Provide students with relevant resources.

Frontend Web Developer, Remote, 2021 to present

- Collaborate with developers and designers in building dummy projects to practice our skills and gain experience
- Assist teammates when needed
- Help Manage and organize the workflow of the project

EDUCATION

LANGUAGES

ARABIC - NATIVE ENGLISH - ADVANCED FRENCH - BEGINNER GERMAN - BEGINNER

Master Degree in Civil Engineering Rafik Hariri University - 2018

Bachelor Degree in Civil Engineering University of Illinois, 2004